Kyle Turchik

Full Portfolio: kturchik.github.io

kturchik@sbcglobal.net (951) 316-1112

Summary

Motivated and dynamic programmer with 4+ years of experience in game development for PC, mobile, and consoles. Proven leader driven by collaboration with multidisciplinary teams. Recognized for being versatile, inspired, and meticulous. Seeking challenging work in tools, UI, graphics, or gameplay programming.

EXPERIENCE

ARVADA LABS | R&D Engineer (tiny.cc/arvadalabs)

01/2018 - PRESENT

Implement core gameplay features and research technology for an augmented reality multiplayer card game.

- ♦ Coordinate between teams of artists and engineers to streamline integration of custom assets.
- ♦ Profile and optimize code base for performance and memory efficiency on mobile devices.

BLIZZARD ENTERTAINMENT | Software Engineer Intern

06/2017 - 09/2017

Developed a rich single-page web application using WebGL with React and Node.js.

- ♦ Created a 3D rendered globe displaying large real-time data streams from Battle.net websockets.
- ♦ Improved rendering performance, using object pooling and object-oriented patterns with WebGL.
- ♦ Enhanced the project by developing a key feature, outside the initial scope, during a hackathon.
- ♦ Implemented detailed UX designs and animations with Javascript and CSS.
- ♦ Collaborated directly with artists, program managers, and fellow engineers in an Agile/Scrum environment, utilizing JIRA to coordinate tasks, Jenkins for CI/CD, and Git for code sharing and reviews.

GOOGLE APPLIED CS PROGRAM | *Student Programmer* (*g.co/appliedcsskills*) **04/2016 – 06/2016** Created Android games with Java and Android Studio as part of a pilot program for a select group of students that reinforces concepts from data structures and algorithms, as well as artificial intelligence.

PROJECTS & AWARDS

Augmented Realms | Independent Team Project

12/2017 - PRESENT

Developing, with Unity and C#, the world building tools, RPG gameplay systems, UI, and client-side network for a multiplayer augmented reality app designed to enhance tabletop RPG gaming using Android and iOS devices.

inVRasion | Independent Team Project

09/2017 - PRESENT

Building, with Unity and C#, the UI, AI, player movement, and weapon mechanics for an asymmetric multiplayer virtual reality FPS game in development for the HTC Vive and PlayStation VR.

Elemental Fury | 3RD Place Overall - BeachHacks

04/2017

Implemented, with Unity and C#, the client-side network using Photon Unity Networking, player controls, and spell mechanics for a multiplayer virtual reality game using networked HTC Vive devices.

Battle of the Bards | 2ND Place Overall & Best Game - HackPoly

02/2017

Created, with Unity and C#, the UI, gameplay mechanics, procedural audio, and particle systems for a RPG/rhythm game, interfacing with artists and designers to execute their vision for the game and integrate all original assets.

ORGANIZATIONS

Student Game Developer Alliance | Founder, Committee Chair (sqda.io)

02/2017 - PRESENT

Founded the largest student-organized game development association in California focused on inspiring and facilitating game development for 200+ students from 9 universities by hosting game jams and educational

Cal Poly Pomona Game Design & Development Club | President

03/2016 - 06/2017

Lead a new student club dedicated to preparing students for careers in game development, mentoring 60+ students by hosting workshops and coordinating large studio-like teams of multidisciplinary students to develop

TECHNICAL SKILLS

Languages: (4+ years) C# ♦ C++ ♦ Java (2 years) JavaScript ♦ Python ♦ Lua ♦ HTML/CSS
Tools: WPF/WinForms ♦ GIT ♦ .NET ♦ Visual Studio ♦ Unity ♦ Unreal ♦ OpenGL ♦ Jenkins ♦ JIRA
Key Concepts: Game Development ♦ Mobile (Android/iOS) ♦ 3D Graphics ♦ Memory Management
♦ Object-Oriented Programming ♦ Computer Networks ♦ Linear Algebra ♦ AR/VR ♦ Agile Development

EDUCATION

Bachelor of Science, Computer ScienceCalifornia State Polytechnic University, Pomona, CA

Cum Laude (Major GPA: 3.6) (Graduation: December 2017)